<resources>
    <string name="app_name">RadinasApp</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="section_format">Hello World from section: %1$d</string>
    <string name="teethpictureclickable">teethPictureClickable</string>
    <string name="select">select</string>
    <string name="division">\u00F7</string>


    <string name="Lidocaine">Lidocaine is rapidly metabolized by the liver and less than 10% of a dose is excreted unchanged in the urine. Oxidative N-dealkylation, a major pathway of metabolism, results in the metabolites monoethylglycinexylidide and glycinexylidide. The pharmacological/toxicological activities of these metabolites are similar to but less potent than Lidocaine. The primary metabolite in urine is a conjugate of 4-hydroxy-2, 6-dimethylaniline.

The elimination half-life of Lidocaine following an intravenous bolus injection is typically 1.5 to 2 hours. There are data that indicate that the half-life may be 3 hours or longer following infusions of greater than 24 hours.

Because of the rapid rate at which Lidocaine is metabolized, any condition that alters liver function, including changes in liver blood flow, which could result from severe congestive heart failure or shock may alter Lidocaine kinetics. The half-life may be two-fold or more greater in patients with liver dysfunction. Renal dysfunction does not affect Lidocaine kinetics, but may increase the accumulation of metabolites.

Therapeutic effects of Lidocaine are generally associated with plasma levels of 6 to 25 μmole/L (1.5 to 6 mcg free base per mL). The blood to plasma distribution ratio is approximately 0.84. Objective adverse manifestations become increasingly apparent with increasing plasma levels above 6 mcg free base per mL.

The plasma protein binding of Lidocaine is dependent on drug concentration and the fraction bound decreases with increasing concentration. At concentrations of 1 to 4 mcg free base per mL, 60 to 80 percent of Lidocaine is protein bound. In addition to Lidocaine concentration, the binding is dependent on the plasma concentration of the α-1-acid glycoprotein.

</string>
</resources>
